SALMAN INAYAT

FRONT END WEB DEVELOPER

+92 3110440150

✓ salmaninayat1999@gmail.com

http://salmaninayat.vercel.app

https://www.linkedin.com/in/salman -inayat-69a634197/

https://github.com/Salman-Inayat

SUMMARY

Creative Front End Developer with 3 years of experience in blending the art of design with skill of programming to deliver an immersive and engaging user experience through efficient website development, proactive feature optimization, and relentless debugging.

TECHNICAL SKILLS



SOFT SKILLS



CERTIFICATIONS

- Full-Stack Web Development with React Specialization | Coursera
- The Web Developer Bootcamp 2020 | Udemy

WORK EXPERIENCE

RESEARCH ASSISTANT IOT LAB SEECS, NUST | 04/2021 - Present

- Developed a segmentation model with the team which segments an image with accuracy of 95.738%.
- Integrated machine learning into React application for image processing.
- Developed a web portal with React.js and Node.js to segment, crop and classify the image and display results to the user.

OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTOR Navidrome Music Server | 03/2021 - Present

- Worked closely with open-source contributors to maintain the project and fixing bugs.
- Implemented enhancements that improved functionality of the system.
- Implemented fixes to the application to make it responsive on smaller screens using React.js with Material UI PR #1071

FRONT END WEB DEVELOPER Hactric Solutions | 08/2020 - 10/2020

- Coordinated with UI/UX designers to code front-end design and create highly responsive web-based user interfaces that accommodated all user requirements.
- Contributed to website development using React.js and Node.js for a 34% increase in client's sales.
 Link: https://jahangiriassociates.com.pk
- Fixed bugs from existing websites and implemented enhancements that significantly improved web functionality and speed

PROJECTS

- Developed my personal portfolio website using Next.js and Material UI which achieves a lighthouse score of 94
- Developed a Point of Sales application for a client which uses machine learning to identify the customer and stores his data.

EDUCATION

National University of Sciences And Technology Islamabad, Pakistan

BE Software Engineering | Sep 2018 - Present